No booze. No sex. No drugs. No way.
Sister Act is a music, comedy film directed by Emile Ardolino.
A Reno singer witnesses a mob murder and the cops stash her in a
nunnery to protect her from the mob's hitmen.
The mother superior does not trust her, and takes steps
to limit her influence on the other nuns.
Eventually the singer rescues the failing choir and begins helping with community
projects, which gets her an interview on TV—and identification by the mob.
Deloris Van Cartier / Sister Mary Clarence, played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Mother Superior, played by Maggie Smith.
Sister Mary Patrick, played by Kathy Najimy.
Sister Mary Robert, played by Wendy Makkena.
Sister Mary Lazarus, played by Mary Wickes.
Vince LaRocca, played by Harvey Keitel.
Sister Act is a 1992 American musical crime comedy film directed by Emile
Ardolino and written by Paul Rudnick (billed as Joseph Howard).
It stars Whoopi Goldberg as a lounge singer forced to hide in a
convent after being placed in a witness protection program.
It also features Maggie Smith, Kathy Najimy, Wendy
Makkena, Mary Wickes, and Harvey Keitel.
Receiving mixed to favorable reviews, Sister Act was one of the most financially successful comedies
of the early 1990s, grossing $231.6 million worldwide against a $31 million budget.
Its success extended to the home video market, and it was the
most rented film of 1993 in the United States.
The film spawned a franchise, which consists of the critically panned 1993 sequel Sister
Act 2: Back in the Habit and a musical adaptation, which premiered in 2006.
A third film is in development for Disney+.
The film explores themes of concert, nun, church
choir, witness protection, gospel.
The tone is lighthearted.